Heather.
Hey Gary, I wait.
Hey guys.
Hello.
Oh, we've got Quorum.
Sweet.
Gang's all here.
Hey, gang is all there.
I created a summary this time.
Did you actually post it this time?
I think so.
Did anybody see that funny video I shared?
Yes.
I was having a, I sometimes like when I'm in a mood to like.
Oh, you mean the one about Valphine?
Yeah.
Ah, yeah.
Yeah, that's great.
Yes.
A dragon defeated, a barbed tempted, and a barbarian's vengeance.
Yeah, so what I really loved was how it interpreted your guys mocking me for my AI-generated slop.
I don't mock you.
Only Mendonol does, right?
It didn't really matter.
I didn't do it into one veteran fled muttering, and Ser Kaelen said to reply, so suspiciously polished, it practically had a PRT
interpreted your mockery of the comment in the AI just caused me to die laughing.
Anyway, all right, let's go to rule 20.
So the first and most important thing to do is you gain a level.
Oh, dear.
That's going to slow down.
Well, I figure since we're partly all here, we can do that.
Yeah.
I'm going to have to do that eventually.
So I'd rather have everybody at the right level than somebody complaining that is that fair.
Is that balanced?
Not that.
Poor David doesn't get to level his own character.
You'll have to do it for him.
I'll say that everybody but Vukradin gained a level.
Well, yeah, he didn't get any fair trade organic experience points.
Yep.
Oh, I can now do radiant damage.
Well, that's fun.
So how does that work?
How do you level up?
If you go into DD Beyond and you go, you see, you're going to see your icon of your character.
You're going to see manage.
Click on that.
Yep.
It'll open up a sidebar on the right.
On the right, there should be one as one of them should say the word levels.
And you could add another class that you like, right?
Yep.
You can do whatever you want.
It's DD.
You can break the game.
It's not that hard.
I thought that's what it was, but I can edit it.
It's a lot easier than you think it would be.
No, I fully believe that the game is just fundamentally broken, and that's fine.
It's fun.
I worry about people who are bragging about, like, well, I broke it this way.
I'm like, okay, dude, like, it's not a, you know, it's like saying I was able to, you know, dropkick a toddler.
Oh, okay.
I was confused by you bring it up because to me, like, breaking DD isn't the stupidest, easy thing to do.
Like, have your job as a GMS, like, to find out how your players broke the game through a series of cascading optimizations that you didn't follow along the way.
Yeah, it's no fire.
I enjoy it.
I don't play that game.
I know you don't.
We established you play that game.
I'm a purist.
I sent in Discolda screenshot of what I'm seeing, but I don't see the how to level up.
Wait, do you have any?
It says manage character and levels on the right side panel.
I thought that was taking me to the to all the characters that I own.
No, okay.
I see.
Now that's managed this character and his levels.
Right.
I can understand that.
Caska DM question.
Of course you may ask more.
Of course you may.
Rule 20.
I'm not sure that I can fully parse this text.
Which one?
I just pasted a third level piece to me in feature.
Oh, hold on.
So let me get to the, let me log into the game.
You know, what I will do is I'll just share it in here.
But no, it's fine.
I just, I was futzing around.
I got distracted.
It turns them into a pack.
I can add elemental damage to my weapon.
Yes.
So, what is your question?
So, it says you can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus.
Yeah, so three times a day.
Three times.
You can forge a bond three times a day?
Yeah.
Or you gain the D4 several times per day.
It says, no, the D4 is once per turn.
So I assume it's the bond can be formed three times a day.
Yeah, so I can forge the bond three times a day, and then we could just add D4s to all of our roles.
Yes, but they have to add more.
That seems a bit powerful.
Yes, but you have to be at peace with each other.
We're not exactly our party.
You're not at peace with each other.
I think that's the thing the party's going to have to decide.
I'm pretty much at peace with the world.
Soma's at peace with everybody but the absolutist naturalists.
Yeah, fuck Adabra.
Just yeah.
So let me show you the sixth level feature for this too.
That's pretty good.
Yeah, both these are.
Yeah, these are really good abilities.
I don't think there's.
I can just turn bear at swipes.
But I don't understand why you haven't used it so far, because the first one is a third-level piece domain feature.
Because I forgot.
Yeah, when you go look at the level bill, you're like, oh, crap, I've had this.
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah, so it's essentially three times per day.
And you can only use the D4 once per turn.
Uh-oh, cat's whining.
So it's the party can use the D4 once per turn, or each character can use the D4 once per turn.
Well, any bonded creature, the creature can roll.
So any creature.
Each creature can add the D4 no more than once per turn.
It's basically a reaction almost, but it doesn't consume a reaction.
No.
So it's like a permanent always-on, but not quite as powerful part of inspiration.
It's a bless.
It's a variation of bless.
Yeah.
Okay.
And then the sixth-level one is cool, but just to be clear, it's a blus spell.
It's a bluspell.
Sorry about the cat.
It's fine.
We love cats.
So then,
Brewbarry.
Yes.
If you then see that sixth-level feature, it basically lets you anytime someone else is going to take damage, you can teleport next to them and take the damage.
Where is that?
It's in the roll 20.
Begin folder and brainball among people who are peaceful.
Or, you know, the bear can use it too, I guess.
I guess the question is like, who's the who has more hit points available for tanking, I guess?
It might be me now.
Let me see.
Wow.
The sixth level one is actually more cool.
The first one is basically blush.
It's like you get three extra spell castings of blus.
Okay.
Well, it seems powerful to me.
No, I mean, it's not trivial, but I mean, I think we have to say canonically why you didn't use it.
Like, you didn't use it because
we're going to figure that out.
Yeah.
We have to have a canonical reason why you didn't use it.
In some ways, it's kind of like when you discovered Thistle had the ability to shoot twice in a round.
You can shoot more than one, Aaron?
Do we have to review all of your abilities?
Yeah, apparently.
I'm playing one-dimensional chess these days.
You're playing checkers.
All right.
Nice.
Works.
Let's see.
Have I seen an owl bear by chance?
No.
How caught?
They're not that common?
All right.
No, I mean, I just haven't rolled up an owl bear.
I mean, that could be a quest you could go on and go find an owl bear.
I mean, it is going to be a.
Let's see.
Six level.
Oh, no.
What challenge rating is an owl bear?
Oh, challenge rating three.
All right.
I'm not there yet.
Yeah, I'm gonna have to figure out where to track this stuff.
All right.
Can I make another DM request?
Of course.
Dude, that's what I'm here for.
Okay.
Go for it.
So, my question is: how does this spell interact with our extra planar encounters?
Which spell is I'm going to send it to the same destination.
Send it to the roll 20.
Abjuration.
What's the question?
How does it interact with planar?
How does it interact with our enemy people that are twisted?
Oh, so you're saying, like, how does it interact with the planar aberrations you've been encountering along the way?
Yeah.
So if they're outside of planar disruption, like they just happen to be walking in the street, it works normally.
Uh-huh.
But if it's in the middle of a planar disruption,
then I will have to come up with some rules.
It also has a casting time of one minute, which is a little bit awkward.
That is very awkward.
Yeah, I might not choose that, but
that's good for rituals.
If you need to protect yourselves.
If you're going to go into combat, no, no, I'm just saying it's a spell that is useful if you're going to defend a location.
It's rather than.
Let's see.
I don't think that spell has ritual on it.
No, no, it doesn't.
It doesn't.
It's useful if you're about to do a ritual.
It's not a utility spell, is what I'm trying to say.
For example, if the party, if you needed to create a safe zone for a short rest and you were being attacked by all these creatures, you could have the party try to defend an area for about a minute while you cast it.
Or you can use it to imprison a creature as well, right?
Because it says you can use it in a reverse direction.
So if you want to capture a creature and question it, that's also a possibility.
Like a tampere jail.
Yeah.
So it has its uses, but it's not an in-the-middle of combat kind of thing.
It's a good candidate for a scroll.
So this is what my DND assistant is telling me.
Put it in Discord.
Would you put it in Discord?
It's the answer from my DND assistant, LLM.
It's trained on DND5E rules.
Ah, so Fey Plane doesn't affect Drow or elves or members of the Seeley and then Seeley court.
So only me.
Why?
Oh, well, because we've got a Drow and a Seeley, right?
No, no, it doesn't affect.
I'm saying, sorry, it doesn't affect you either because you're also from the neutral plane.
I'm just saying Fae creatures aren't affected.
Yeah.
I think I've picked my spell.
Which is.
I will show you.
I think the cat disagrees.
Whatever spell you think you picked, it was the wrong one.
That one.
Oh, yeah, this is a good spell.
Yeah, that's a lot of healing.
A lot of point impact with a lot of stats on that spell.
Yeah, no, no, it's a good spell.
It's particularly useful if the cleric is on a cleric who's useless at combat.
But it creates that sort of dilemma.
Do you do that or shield guardians?
That's right.
But some fights one and other fights the other.
Yeah.
Like Spirit Guardians does a lot more, has a lot more utility in a spell in a combat with multiple enemies.
It's not very useful if you're fighting a dragon who's flying.
For example.
Yeah.
So if you choose to restore hit points to one creature, does it count as an action, a Buddhist action?
Yeah, no action at all.
Counts the magic action, right?
Magic action, okay.
When you create the aura and at the start of each of your turns, well, you just no, that doesn't say it consumes an action.
Yeah.
I mean, when it's casted, it costs an action, but then past that, it's just concentration and free per turn.
One more spell slot.
Yeah, who can't turn down Robertify?
Why not?
Oh, since you guys will appreciate the snark in this, especially Wade.
I love Snark.
Yeah, that's why I said, especially Wade.
I was being snarky about it.
We are now in the first wave of AI's insidification cycle.
Claude has gone from having a PhD in your pocket to a bumbling intern while flat billing for enterprise users will now become usage-based.
Everyone knew the subsidies wouldn't last, but this is ending faster than expected.
At least wait until the IPO.
Yeah, I'm mourning the death of Open Claw.
That was really sad for me.
Oh, when they went to the new billing team tier, yeah, they gave me $120 and Credit is like, We're sorry, you can't do what you've been doing anymore, but here's $120.
I want to do what I was doing.
It's all right.
Oh, I did find something that those of you who are rule lawyers would find fascinating, or people who like gaming systems in general.
I forgot to show you.
So, somebody decided to do something really insane, which is to basically get a formal model for the Dungeons and Dragons rules.
Like a computer science theoretical formal model.
Oh, okay.
And so it basically implements the full model.
And it can do like really crazy things as a result.
Like
it's so if you wanted to like see like like it can answer very precise questions about the rules and like and and more importantly because it knows the rules it can run full combat simulations precisely right there's like no ambiguity so if you go there and try it out there's like there's a couple of like that you can actually it's got some encounters where you can click and watch as it runs through the encounter it's pretty neat neat yeah i i like i said it was it was cute i was like and of course it only supports the srd rules so it doesn't support all of the rules and the other but the other fun pun is that if you're into like the whole rules in like is like the guy spent a lot of time trying to figure out what the rules were and you know this result discovered you know ambiguities in the rules and that you know conflicts well you describe those that wouldn't be dv yeah
did anyone ever play with speed factor
not me and and if so why
because encumbrance wasn't boring enough i don't know encumbrance actually made sense in the original game but it was it wasn't the game we play now it was essentially a dungeon crawl exploration game yeah you should rest also you were expected to travel with a lot of mercenaries right like you were expected to travel with mooks
and that's why creatures like the doppelganger existed i think
think i actually got this working
It's raw HTML on this shit.
Oh, God.
DD Beyond.
No.
All right.
Mine was easy.
Oh, yeah.
I've just been spending all my time trying to get the dang staff translated or transliterated into the game or into the UI.
Yeah, sure enough.
It is.
So, what is Dave's status tonight?
He is on a planet, I believe.
Yeah.
Okay.
And we were playing without him?
Yes, we have enough.
We have Quorum.
Okay.
So I just want Quorum.
We will keep it.
He did not gain in level.
He is in which we'll call it.
Sex 3M.
No, he, no, there was conflict gold, so he didn't know what to do with it.
All right.
So the pirate, the party is, and I, Stefan, are you with us, or are you still going through your character?
No, I'm here.
Sorry.
Okay, just, I didn't know if you were busy.
Feel free to keep doing whatever you're doing.
I just wanted to make sure that you didn't.
I just, I'm not a question.
I just want to make sure that we didn't like you were you needed something or something.
All right.
So when we last left our noble adventures, they were at the Aspire Hold.
The dragon was dead.
Oh.
And so then there was a question of like, do I get any body parts?
Oh, yeah.
We wanted to harvest.
Yeah, antagonistic.
Yes.
Yeah, you missed the dragon fight.
Yes, yes.
You killed the dragon.
It's kind of anticlimactic.
Okay.
It's not my fault you guys made your saving throws.
And you didn't.
And I didn't.
Like, I'm sorry.
I'll make sure to make the dragon fight sport memorable next time.
It's okay.
Oh.
Selfie has a special ability to.
Okay, I missed that.
Yes, yes.
Oh, yeah.
So you should look at your.
Did you guys look at the?
I put some notes in your character in the chat.
I definitely saw mine.
Yes.
Please look at yours.
Yeah, I did.
I added it to my character sheet.
My point to you is that your God is rewarding you for your actions.
Well, of course he did.
No, no, like for your for your, he's rewarding you.
You gain the sense that your God is pleased with your new direction of Lothander's church.
Right.
That he senses something important, that you are now important in his mind.
All right.
I just want to be clear.
Stefan, I just need to tell you something.
Since you did not change the backstory, Brewbarry was snookered by Thistle.
That's why some of these things are the way they were.
Right.
Was snookered by what?
Gary's previous character was a fairy that was a ranger and flew around a lot.
Oh, okay.
Right.
And so in the Storm of the Kings, Storm of the Last Camp Adventure, the party went around stealing artifacts from all the various Garadian tribes.
Okay.
Correctly.
It's canonically, Thistle stole an artifact from your tribe.
Okay.
Got it.
And this missing artifact and its disappearance when Brewbarry was on guard.
Oh, okay.
So that's why.
Right.
So this one's deliberate.
So this is why when you saw the Goodberry,
I had a reaction.
Yes.
Okay.
Right.
And so the important point is as Brewbarry, so Brewbarry, as he, as you, you know, it's has gotten, you know, suddenly feels like he's starting to realize the world, there's lying in the world and there's cheating in the world and the world is not what it is.
And there's like all these people using magical manipulations trying to control him.
Right.
And so as he does more of that, he gains more.
He gains more of power, so to speak.
By the way, but since you inherited this character, if you don't like this, just tell me we can change it.
This is great.
I just wanted to make sure that, you know, just so you know what it is.
So, yeah, so he's so the key insight behind Brewbarry is that he got bamboozled by, he got kicked out of his tribe.
Right.
When you were out, we decided I had to do my best Stefan imitation.
He did pretty high.
All right.
And so, and so Brewbarry declared that, you know, before he became, he didn't drink when he was a member, when he was a tribesmen because the alcohol was really bad.
But ever since he joined civilization, he discovered wine and beer.
Of course, he did.
Yes.
And so now he truly appreciates alcohol.
And there's a funny moment where, you know, Valphine Vukradin asks him, so he goes, you didn't drink?
Yes.
What a wasted youth.
Yeah, maybe at some point you should require alcohol for some of these features.
There is some sort of like drunken monk class.
I don't know if that meshes with where you're going with this character, but maybe there's something a monk.
Yeah.
I just wanted you to be aware of why these things are there so that you're not.
So like, I figured it was something that I missed at some point.
Yeah, it's like you missed a lot.
You missed the last two years.
Yeah.
So that's the McGuffin of the Uthguard Barbarian.
We haven't figured out which tribe he is, but I could give you a bunch and you can pick one if you want, if that becomes important to you.
All right.
Okay.
So dragon parts.
Let me go do that.
Okay.
So we're going to need to roll some ability checks.
I just need to remember what the ability can be visibility checks.
All right.
Okay, so the ability check is nature.
I got advantage on that shit.
Okay.
All right.
Roll it.
Well, you can roll it, but let me just roll it and I will tell you what happens.
Are you kidding me?
Did you roll it one?
I roll a double 20.
Yeah.
Double crit on advantage.
I rolled an 18.
Not bad for a barbarian.
That's not a time I wanted to spend a double crit, but I guess we've just perfectly harvested that dragon.
We put him in a bathtub that Oregon harvested.
All right.
Okay.
Well, since you get the double 20, I suppose we should do it's only 120 officially, right?
Okay, so.
Yes, but it's an it's a critical.
So, all right.
Yeah, they were natural 20s, so they're 22s with the bonus.
Okay, so it's 20.
Do you get any bonuses to that?
Or is it plus 20?
Well, it's I have a twelve.
I rolled 20s and I have a plus two.
So it's 22 overall, but they were natural 20s.
And, you know, it's an evangel, so only one of them is in play.
Obviously, the higher one, but it's hard to choose.
All right.
Yeah, I think that if I gave this, you know, Vukradin would resign.
So we, we, we, but it's all right.
So so, okay.
So you get two things.
When the word dragon is uttered, people to think of three things: wings, scales, and breadth.
Located at the back of the black of the dragon's throat is a basket sized of magical liquids that the dragon naturally produces.
While the liquid and their resulting exaltation differ depending on the dragon, they all share the same destructive results.
Harvesting one of these without rupturing them is almost as difficult as killing its host in the first place, but the result.
Right.
Okay.
This is a young adult.
No, sorry.
I'm looking at the wrong age.
Sorry.
All right.
That's okay.
Okay.
Oh, in that case, we can do that.
All right.
Okay, so when the word dragon is blah, blah, blah.
Okay, so you do get the dragon breath pouch.
Basically, it's a one-time dragon breath pouch of a young white dragon.
Oh, Lord.
Dragon breath pouch.
Yes.
It's also worth 1,675 gold pieces.
Oh, you're putting that in?
All right.
1,600 and what?
75.
I don't know.
A pouch of, you know, rethrost or whatever it was.
And is that a single use or is that single use?
It's a single use, yes.
Single use.
I mean, it's like a lot of damage, right?
For a young dragon.
Let's get out of scale-free card.
Yep, yep.
It's basically a very powerful fireball.
All right.
The scales of the young dragon.
Some of these scales are still supple, flexible plates from their wormling gears, particularly if they have not had many chances to molt.
Getting them is easier said than done, however, as not only one must kill a dragon first, they must also manage to find and safely detach the right scales needed to interlock into a functioning set of armor.
Well, I did that.
All right, so that's 1,600.
That's also 1,675 gold pieces.
3,200 gold and call it, you know, put Ubert up in his studio.
Run.
Yeah, so there, there is our so that it can be turned into dragon scale mail.
Dragon scale mail sounds good.
It's part of the ascension kit.
What?
Oh, if Dave were here, you guys would know.
It's a NetHack reference.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
It feels so bad that I don't know these things.
Play more NetHack.
Although, wasn't a Black Dragon better than white?
It depends on what you're.
You usually want silver for reflect, but if you have a shield, then you want gray for magic resist.
Yes, silver and gray are distinct.
This is why I'm unemployable.
No, you're not.
That's not why.
Your brain sits around memorizing.
And it's been too long since I've done NetHack.
Maybe we should get back into it.
You got to get to your Chrono Trigger first.
And Baldur's Gate before that.
Yeah, that's true.
Okay, sorry.
I was actually mistaken.
The magic item is a little bit cooler than it was.
It's not a one-time one-type thing.
Oh, Lord.
So let me just.
You did get the.
This is kind of like the.
Okay, hold on.
I can't want to screw up again because I do screw these things up.
Dragon's Wrath.
All right.
So here's what it is.
Okay, so you can actually, so you can use it either as a one-time thing or you can attempt to craft this.
Sorry, I should have been more specific.
You can try to craft it.
I'll put it in the Discord because this is just too much text for me.
Right.
Let's see.
I have to figure out what the crafting rules for it.
This would be.
Oh, it can be used once per 14 hours.
Yeah, so if you're willing to spend 20,000 gold pieces, you can turn it into this wondrous item.
20,000 gold pieces.
Oh, we can craft it into that.
I see.
Crafted by a Dragon's Breath Pouch.
Okay.
Otherwise, you can use it as a one-time thing.
So we're going to get at least $1,600 for it, or we can spend 20 geek large or, yeah, all right.
Okay, that'd be a pretty good one.
And this is we have the adult-sized one?
The young adult, young adult.
Young adult.
Okay.
I think it's got, I think, oh, sorry, rare.
2,000 gold pieces.
It's not very rare.
The guy who does a typo in the documentation.
It put very rare yucks to young dragon rather than adult dragon.
So 2,000 gold piece.
2 grand.
That's worth it.
Right.
Okay.
So that's what you were able to extract from the dragon.
Pretty good with that.
And are there details about crafting the scales and the scale armor?
You have to find an armor.
Turns out that there is an armor.
Crafting dragon armor is not as complicated.
But let me just check.
You just need a blacksmith.
And I j I just need to find out what dragon scale armor is like.
Dragon scale armor edition.
I have that here this second.
It is
armor scale mail.
It's very rare.
That would be in the 20,000 gold piece range.
All right.
Yeah, so this is medium armor AC15.
It also has other abilities, I think.
Medium is barbarian suitable, right?
So you also get a saving, you get a saving since it's from a white dragon, you get advantage on saving throws against breath weapons of dragons, and you have resistance to cold damage.
Yeah, that'd be really good for Brewbarry.
And additionally, you can focus your census as a magic action to discern the distance and direction to the closest white dragon within 30 miles of yourself.
Wow.
And so what is our cost for doing that crafting?
20K.
Does that really cost 20 grand?
That's a very rare item.
And so, yes, he's put it at 20,000.
But, you know, this is a starting point.
Negotiations, deals, trades, quests, activities can be used to reduce the.
You can do a solid to a blacksmith and get a discount.
There's always some very.
You know, don't forget, you have all those items that you have found.
Perhaps you can return them for rewards.
We have 700 gold.
Yes, I realize that.
Vukradin may decide that the 1600 gold pieces divided by four is worth more.
You may get tempted.
All right.
Okay.
So you managed to take the treasure.
So the next, so where does our party, where do the things hold?
One is that you definitely got the subtext from Ser Kaelen that you're needed back in Phandalin because the Emerald Enclave, things are going down with the Emerald Enclave.
Yeah, so I think the other last time we decided we would go first to Phandalin before we go to Neverwinter, right?
Yes.
So that would be.
There was much debate on that, but yes.
Some light railroading was applied.
Some light.
I just want to be clear.
Consequences.
I'm not complaining.
All right.
Consequences.
So, okay, so this is 30 miles.
All right.
So the fastest path, it's going to two-day journey.
So we assume it all rests, right?
Yes, yes.
Do you go through?
So the question is, do you go through the Mountain Toes Gold Mine or do you head straight?
Oh, do we probably have a reason to stop by and see Don Juan DeMarco, right?
Don Juan's dead, remember?
Oh, right.
God damn.
We still have to go see our dwarven slaves.
They got some gold while we're there.
I don't know.
Yeah.
I wouldn't mind checking in on our gold mine.
I wouldn't mind, okay.
As Vukradin didn't say, strictly speaking, it's his gold mine.
Sure.
And Bony is my horse.
So, you know.
Do you still have the horse?
I just want to make sure.
Yeah.
Bony's bonded to me.
You said that you were going to get him, you know, combat stats at some point.
Oh, right, right, right, right, right.
So there's this rule called sidekicks.
We've got us a wallace again.
How many sidekicks do we have so far?
You only have one right now.
I don't think the guys that we tie up in camp, basically.
Yeah.
I mean, I think Valphine needs to be explained what the word a sidekick means.
I think she's because Sister Kaella is fantastic.
I need the fast sidekick as a cleric, right?
I think you can add it to your character sheet.
If you go to extras and manage extras, you can choose sidekick.
So, yes, you can create a martial sidekick.
This would be clearly not either a warrior sidekick or a warrior sidekick is the you could look at that.
That said DD pend.
Yeah, if you go if you look in DND, hold on.
DB warrior for sure.
There you go.
Sidekicks.
There may be other sidekicks.
They kind of expanded sidekicks to include lots of other variations, but I'm a big fan and just let's keep it simple.
Sure.
But if you guys, if you, if you, if you find something that appeals to you, by all means.
I'll dig into it too.
I need to figure it out.
All right.
I just want the bone horse.
I want him to die and come back over and over and over again because he's just a bone horse.
As far as I'm, he's immortal, right?
Like, he doesn't have death saves or anything.
I assume he just gets like zonked for a little bit.
He's bony.
Yeah, he's bony.
He's a skeleton.
If he dies, he comes back the next day, not right away.
Yeah, that's what I want.
I want to be part necro at this point.
But only for animals, because, you know, nature.
All right.
My own little pet cemetery going on.
Dude, that's kind of starting to creep me out, but funny.
When I look at the sidekick thing, it says 11th level and higher.
Yeah, well, let's worry about that when we get to 11th level.
Oh, okay.
All right.
So it's not a sidekick.
No, it is a sidekick.
What do you mean?
No, it says, like, didn't I, did the link I not give you?
I think I clicked the wrong one.
It just says warriors at the bottom, at the very bottom.
He goes off us.
Oh, so, okay, sorry.
This was not the right link.
Sorry, my bad.
This is the simplified link for why do these people do this to me?
All right.
I will.
If you click on the first thing.
Oh, there we go.
This is the one I wanted.
I see.
This is the one.
I gave you the search doesn't work on DD Beyond.
Here we go.
This is the one I'm looking for.
All right.
So it has, do you see how it works?
The new Tasha's thing.
Yeah.
It's to deal with parties that acquire pets and they want them to come along.
Okay.
All right.
So you arrive at Mountain Toes Gold Mine.
And as you arrive at the gold mine, let's see if something happens.
Sorry.
All right.
You arrive at the gold mine, and there is, in fact, the were rats are sitting outside guarding everything as you sort of expect it.
They are, you know, looking very so.
There's the Whiskered Gang and Zeleen Varnaster is currently very happy to be there.
They're like, you know, they see you, they go, hey, boss!
What's up?
Are you working hard today?
What do you mean, are we working hard today?
Are you keeping the dwarves in their place?
He goes, the boss, do you intimidate him or do you just deliver it flatly?
Flatly.
That actually causes him to panic.
Oh, boy.
Now we're nervous.
They've been working really hard.
I promise you, boss, they've been working really, really hard.
YouTube boss.
Yeah, I mean, like, totally.
This is.
Lathander won't be pleased.
Sure.
They got that cheese delivery.
All right.
Unfortunately, just as he says that.
As fortunately, as he says that, roll an insight or investigation check.
That I can do.
Any one of you.
Well, I got a 22.
I got a natural one.
Natural one plus 10.
We're still on the dragon fight on the map.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Let me put you on the right map then.
Sorry, my bad.
That's okay.
Okay, we're going to do the world map.
Okay.
So you notice that nobody, you notice that there is no sounds of mining going on.
Okay, where are the dwarves?
We need to talk to the dwarves.
I know what's going on.
Do you want you barge right in?
Like, you know, you're done with the bureaucrats, you know, charge right in.
I think that would be appropriate.
Yeah, but it's all mine, isn't it?
I'm just asking what, like, I mean, you might want to carefully reason through it, have a thoughtful discussion.
Let's go to the dwarves.
There are minions.
I mean, like, they're here to do our bidding.
Right.
I'm just asking.
All right.
Okay.
So inside.
Hold on, I had that opened right here.
There we go.
Pardon.
All right.
They're on strike.
God damn it.
Dwarves are on strike.
Yes.
Apparently.
They won't work for Christmas.
The foreman, Dwallan the Grout, Stout Stone Tallow is convinced that the mining operations cannot proceed until a particular Earth Elemental gem is found to bless the new top.
He explains, he approaches Vukradin or the three of you, and he says, Look, you have to understand gold.
A gold vein is shy.
It must be treated with absolute respect.
If you don't treat it with the respect, it doesn't come out.
Did her where people did they come with us?
You barge right past them.
They're choosing to stay outside.
Okay, I'm going to go walk back.
Say, you, come here, come with me.
This can be an intimidating sneaky.
All right, hold on.
Let me get the map.
What is wrong with those dwarves?
I mean, what happened to Rock and Stone?
Yeah, I thought you couldn't stop them from mining usually.
Well, apparently, Stone Tallow believes that, you know, there's a, like, if you just start digging, you won't find the right gold.
It'll just like hide.
Gold is gold.
Hide where?
He goes.
You can ask the other dwarf, Harria, who's the leader there, whether she has any opinions about this.
Yes.
I mean, do the other dwarves agree with his opinion, or is it just a let's remove him problem?
Oh, well, apparently he's the foreman, so he's the guy who knows like the most about where to mine.
Right.
Apparently, he doesn't.
Harria explains, well, look, guys, Dwallan is the best seeker of gold I have ever known.
Right?
He is a, and he's got his little rituals and his little gimmicks and his little things.
You know, it's one of those things where he's got to have his little trinket now.
I do have a solution for this.
Okay.
Go.
If you're willing.
Let's just step outside.
Maybe one of you want to distract Dalwyn, you know, start talk to him.
Leave Vukradin behind.
All right.
So we still need to deal with this were rat who lied to us and need to make sure he understands that you should not be lying to us.
Okay.
So the were-rats are actually intimidated by you because you're a drow who doesn't like who's a cleric of Lathander.
Right.
I'm going to cast my daylight spell.
Okay.
Everybody's eyes.
Everybody's eyes kind of hurt.
It's all bright and sunny.
Do I get advantage on Send Vibe now?
Oh, no, no.
I mean, you are intimidating.
You don't have to roll for like you've intimidated him.
Okay.
The dead pen.
I ruled the dead pen delivery intimidated me.
Are these dwarves mining?
He looks at you like, I'm.
Well, I mean, did you tell me that these dwarves are mining?
Are these words mining?
He goes, boss.
See, I'm not an expert in mining, and I was told by, he points to Harria by her, that this is part of the mining process.
Is there like a minecart?
Is there a minecart here?
There could be.
Let's just say there is.
I mean, I want to go look in the minecart.
Is there gold in the minecart?
Okay.
So did you walk to the minecart, right?
Is that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Is there gold in this minecart?
He looks into it and says, no, but Dwallan says that we need the Earthstone gem before we can get the gold.
So he's saying.
And have you gotten this Earthstone gem for the dwarves?
There's a sudden silence.
Boss, we're paid to protect the mine, not to go on fetch quests.
Fetch quests are a staple of this universe.
The only reason you're protecting the mine is because the mine is useful to us to acquire gold.
If the mine is not producing gold, then you're not doing your job.
Yes.
The purpose of the mine is to produce gold.
That is the goal.
So there's this moment where he's confused and he's going, okay, so what does that mean?
So we can stay here then, right?
Because you don't need the mine, right?
It means pull your fingers out of your rat's ass and do whatever is necessary for the dwarves to be happy miners.
We want to hear did you achieve the business goal?
All right, roll some intimidations here.
There's some KPIs that need to be measured, huh?
Sorry.
Not very impressive.
Well, that's not working.
Can I have an can have advantage?
So if somebody can help you.
Who's helping me?
I'll help you.
Someone's not joining in on the intimidation.
Okay, that's her.
Looks like Brewbarry is helping.
Or maybe I'm helping Brewbarry.
All right, you're helping Brewbarry.
All right.
So what did you roll?
I rolled a 12.
Oh, an eight plus four.
You rate it, rolled a 12.
Yes.
But that was before we decided that I would get advantage if he's helping me.
Okay, so roll for advantage.
Okay, advantage.
So I'll do another roll then, since I've already done one.
Oh, that's much better.
One better.
Okay.
So he goes, the wereats.
Well, boss, I mean, I think you make an excellent point.
I think you're making an excellent point.
But like, I mean, it's rude, but to get this gem, we have to go into the forest where the orcs are.
And this is more of a you guys.
Is that any of my problem?
Am I getting paid with cheese to make sure that the mine is productive?
What am I paying you for?
If all you do is eat the cheese and the mine is not producing gold, then I'm wasting my cheese, aren't I?
You're a waste of cheese.
That's what you are.
Unless you go into the forest, find the gem, get the bloody dwarves to mine.
Cheese.
Is that how you want to be remembered?
You know, were rats, offsprings.
We lost her mic.
Sorry.
Oh, my dad was a waste of cheese.
We lost her mic.
I haven't said anything.
I heard him.
I hear him.
All right.
So I'm sorry.
I mean, that is an inspired moment.
Give yourself an inspiration.
That was inspired.
All right.
That's the.
Sorry.
The, what's his name?
Zeleen goes, you know what?
I think you make an excellent point, Mr.
Boss is the name of the.
Boss.
Yeah.
Mr.
Boss.
And I think he kind of nods over there to several of the wereats.
They can go find the emerald gem.
I think that's totally within contractual obligations.
Yeah, the how is of no concern to me.
I think we could make that happen, Mr.
Boss.
So we both agree you get the what and the why, and you're going to get it done.
Yes, yes, when being right now.
Yeah, he goes, he kind of like, you know, does that thing from like Admiral Piett in Empire Strikes Back after they're collecting Admiral Ozzel's body points to he turns around and points to someone, you go why are you here?
You heard what the boss said.
Go get the emerald.
Yeah, and I'm like with my halberd in my hand, tapping it in my hand.
That means chop, chop.
Absolutely.
He screams at them that they haven't even done it yet.
I assure you, Mr.
Boss, this is completely taken care of.
All right.
So you keep the gold rolling.
We'll keep the cheese rolling and we'll both be friends forever.
Yes.
Excellent.
All right.
Okay.
Let's talk to that other dwarf who had the solution for this.
Make sure that the solution is what we just prescribed to those were rats.
She's kind of like going, I was going to propose you give me some money so I can go buy a fake gem, but you know what?
Your solution is way better, man.
All right.
Let's call the fake gem plan B and in case the were rats fail, which I have high expectation of them failing.
They're just rats.
So she goes, yeah, I think, you know, like, yeah, so if you just give me, like, I don't know, some 50 gold pieces, I think I could secure the right kind of fake gem that would convince Dwallin that, you know, he's got what he needs.
He's very weird.
He really needs those things.
But I have to tell.
Did you just.
Oh, Gary can't hear us.
All right.
Well, let me just check.
Did you try to intimidate again?
Intimidate who?
Did you just roll intimidation?
Or did that.
That's an old roll.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry.
That was the one that Gary helped him with when he gained advantage.
Okay.
So, Horia, let me just bring Horia over there.
I'm back there.
Okay.
Excellent.
So Horia is like, well, for 50 gold pieces, I can assure you that we can make this happen.
But you want gold.
You're working a gold mine.
Yeah, but like to work the gold mine, I have to dig the gold mine.
You see the hieronym of what you're just saying, right?
Yeah.
Just skim a little.
Exactly.
She gets distracted.
She goes, you know, ask him to take a shower by the river or whatever.
She pauses and says, wait, hold on.
Look, I'm a big believer in contractual obligations and procedures and rules.
And if you'll notice that we have a no-skimming clause that Mr.
Vukradin insisted we put in.
How about the barbarian in your face, Clause?
Did you read that in your contract?
She goes, I'm perfectly happy to have an addendum signed by Mr.
Brewbarry.
Thumbprints.
All right.
I'm out of ink.
How about I draw a little blood from you so we can sign that addendum?
I think we could assume that the addendum is signed.
Yes.
And she pauses and she kind of tries to lean down to whisper, but then realizes that she's leaning down to your toe because you're seven foot tall and she's like three foot tall.
She kind of work on plan A, you work on plan B, right?
So Horia says, so here's the deal.
According to the Brewbarry addendum, the 50 gold pieces that will be moved around are totally within the contractual obligations and we will not be pursued for any missing funds.
So 50 gold pieces.
I'm a barbarian, but I can count.
She goes, I am a stickler for procedures and rules.
Yeah, she sees Vukradin over there.
And I do suggest we keep this little addendum between ourselves.
Yeah.
Yeah, let's do that.
She goes, I don't think Mr.
Vukradin would be open to these kinds of negotiations.
What do you mean?
It's honest work.
You'll using gold from the gold mine to buy a fake gem so that we can mine more gold?
Sure, but just for humor, just can you could someone yeah, and remember, this is plan B.
If plan A works, the 50 gold mines are put back into the pot what Mr.
Boss meant.
That's me.
Yes, all right.
Sounds like a plan.
All right.
Okay.
By the way, we need to roll and we need to add a D4 to that Intimidate check.
Okay, well, he's successfully intimidated, so we don't need to do that this time.
Sure.
Why an additional default?
Because he has his new special ability.
His free bless, his three free blesses.
Yeah.
Almost going to D4 to it, right?
Yeah, so he can use it bless.
I think.
Got it.
Yeah, it's basically a bless.
You bless up to three creatures within range.
Whenever a target makes an attack roll, saving through before the spell ends, the target adds 1d4 to the attack roll or save.
Oh.
Oh, a bond on them for 10 minutes or until you use this feature again.
Yeah, to add a different set of group people.
So suppose you wanted to, right?
Suppose you were with a group of five, you had five people in your party, and you only could use it with three, right?
Right.
So it lasts 10 minutes.
10 minutes.
Last 10 minutes.
So for bless lasts one minute.
Right.
And if you want to do more than three people, you would have to be, you burn higher-level slots.
Ah.
Okay.
All right.
Right.
So this party-wide, 10-minute bless, yeah.
So party-wide 10-minute plus.
Okay.
Sorry.
Just want to make sure I do this right.
Plus, we can add article inspiration for 1d8.
Right.
So, yeah.
So it's a plus.
It's basically a bless spell.
All right.
But the party has to be friendly.
If we're not sure, we'll roll, you know, I mean, no, Vukradin is friends with everybody.
So this is really about the rest of you.
He wants to be friends with everybody.
I spent a lot of time trying to understand Vukradin.
Vukradin is genuinely naive.
Yes.
The essence of Vukradin is a good, naive person.
He assumes the naivete is absolute.
I feel everyone's at peace with me.
Yeah, well, yes, until you offer training rituals for people who want to torture people.
They're not stabbing me with poison daggers.
I mean, like, that's at peace.
Yeah.
It could be Hannah's gold, too, right?
Okay.
So after you collect.
Oh, and since you made through this quest, I do actually, I spent some time trying to figure out how much money you guys would be making from this.
So if somebody could make a note.
I took some notes on this one.
Okay.
So, okay.
So I know.
Okay.
So,
all right.
He, it's going, it's going to be so.
Next time you come by, I'll tell you how much money it is.
It's Dwallin is very, you know, everybody's very happy with the data and the paperwork.
All right.
The TPS reports have been filed correctly.
Yes, yes.
And so like within a few days, the whereats promise that everything will be taken care of.
You know, like it will, it will all be it will all be handled.
Good.
All right.
Excellent.
And no bloodshed.
We will not need these concrete overshoes.
All right.
So you arrive in Phandalin.
We won't have time to play the whole encounter, but that's fine.
We will do that next week.
This week was a paper.
There's an encounter in Phandalin.
What?
No, there's a whole Emerald Enclave.
Yeah.
Situation.
The Emerald Enclave is a situation.
Well, it's going to get interesting, hopefully.
They're sided with like the demons.
No, they're not.
Wow.
They're in a some fat.
Yes, there's parts of them that are.
All right.
So you arrive in Phandalin.
So you should be seeing Phandalin right now.
We do.
All right.
And I presume you your arrival, as you walk into town, there's like people step outside and cheer.
You know, there's like go-teen-go kind of thing.
They like us.
Yeah, Sassano, the Smithy, the Barthon and Barthen's provisions.
You know, there's a few of the kids are out like, you know, high-fiving you.
You know, like the.
We brought the dragon parts as evidence, right?
Right, right, right.
Yeah.
Because they wanted us to kill the dragon, right?
Right.
And so Harbin goes, This is exactly why we needed a privy council with the extraordinary talents of Mr.
Vukradin.
We let him take credit, that cute little guy.
Yeah, he goes over.
And without, I just cannot stress enough how with his undefatigable support and his management to lead this group of heroic adventures, the threat of dragons has abated.
Yes.
There's like, you know, polite applause, you know.
And so, without any further ado, Spider-Man, I think we should absolutely throw a wonderful festival today in the town green to celebrate today's events and to make a festival.
A festival that Spider-Man agrees.
And so, you know, there's like immediately, like, people start.
He says, we will, you know, start this like he calls out to some help, and there's like, they're starting to put together a whole like party area on the town green.
Is there any free beverages?
Libations will be present.
Spider-Man, Spider-Man says, for you, Brewbarry, since you saved the town, I'm going to bring out the good stuff.
Yes, please.
Don't put his drinks on the house, or you know, finally.
He goes, I always gave you the good stuff.
This is the very good stuff.
And Brewbarry, I only have two barrels, so you're just going to have to remember that.
It's not magic wine, is it?
It's regular wine.
It's just regular wine, but it's very special.
I'm very proud of you.
I'll be the judge of that.
Okay, so while that's going on, Ser Kaelen approaches you.
And he goes, Ah, the heroes of the heroes of Phandalin.
He like, you know, says, Vukradin, our associate member of the Lord's Alliance and his wondrous friends, Brewbarry Soma Valphine of the cult of Lathunder.
Right?
Meanwhile, you're two cults.
Okay.
We'll keep with that.
I'm sorry, like the word cult is what polytheistic religions refer to themselves.
They were called cults.
We were going to do the parade of self-flagellation here in a minute, anyway.
Well, Britain when they hear you here show up and they're very excited and they're going, oh, the glorious blinding pain.
Yes.
I mean, they're like ecstatic.
Like, do you encourage them?
Oh, yes.
Why wouldn't you?
I think what I'm trying to say is they're really like sort of like, oh, Ser Kaelen says, Soma, we must speak urgently.
Me?
Yes, you.
Is this about Adabra?
It's about the Emerald Enclave.
So, yes.
He says, Adabra has called a conclave of the druids of the area.
Has she?
What is she planning?
Is she trying to bring them all to her side?
Well, perhaps we should go to a private location to chat.
Bring your friends as well.
I just don't want everyone to be hearing.
There may be spies.
Give them time to set up the festivities, right?
Right.
So anybody who can wants to conjoin.
He's not trying to do anything harm.
He just doesn't want to have a public conversation.
Yeah.
I mean, you can go and use the temple if you want, for example.
Sure.
My loyal followers are discreet.
Well, at least they're taking sacraments right now.
No.
Fine.
I can't seem to.
I think I hit the bug in their UI render.
How hard can it possibly be to do features in the system now that you have clot?
Like, seriously.
You should be cranking out features a lot faster.
You forget that management exists and management will retard anything.
That's what I was trying to say without saying it.
So thank you for saying that.
You know, all management is purpose of management is to slow things down.
Partner always said managers are like assholes.
All they can really do is hold shit in, and if you piss them off, they dump it all on you.
All right.
Okay.
So, Ser Kaelen, you are at the Temple of the Fallon, the Thander, the Searing Pain of Justice.
Ser Kaelen explains urgently that Adabra has found out about what really happened at the Whispering Grove.
That was where you guys killed the Treant?
Yeah.
And Vukradin lied to her.
Yeah, Vukradin.
Yes.
And so he goes, she has decided she has gone with her allies and is going to attempt to convince the Druids that your reckless interventionism has brought harm to the forests.
Harm to the forests.
It's the naturalists that have brought harm.
She knows that.
So Soba says, I agree with you, but you must attend.
He looks at your staff.
I am told that this is some magical staff of some symbolism and power amongst the druids in the area.
Yeah.
Well, I don't know.
I don't know specifically about in the area, but it's, I don't know.
I was told by my friends among the druids.
Yeah.
I'm starting to suspect that Adabra isn't part of this realm and her and her kind are something else.
He goes, so my dear boy, my dear Tortle, and you're wise and Adabra is not an evil person, but she is a person who believes that she's, how shall I explain this?
She's confused.
She sees the harm that was caused by those who defended against the dragons and thinks that the problem was that the defenders against the dragons were the problem, not the dragons.
She sees the planar incursions as not the symptoms because she never experienced those symptoms.
She experienced the consequences of war.
Yeah, she's bringing her own war out here.
Yeah, so she's not evil.
She's just misguided.
And unfortunately, in her misguided passion, she's managed to acquire enough of a group.
And I worry that there may be consequences for you personally and for the community as a whole.
The Lords Alliance and the Lords Alliance doesn't want to intervene.
And the Order of the Gauntlet, although we would like to intervene, cannot because, well, the War of the Dragons and then the War of the Giants and then the War.
Let's just say there's fewer of us to go around these days.
It's all on us, huh?
He goes, you're standing, and apparently, you're standing with that staff might be able to tip the balance.
I've also heard rumors.
I'm standing with the druids.
I'm barely a druid myself.
Yes, but apparently, this staff is, I don't look, look, druids have rituals and beliefs that I, as a, as a, as a, as a, as a man of sword and action, don't always understand.
So, so you, you must go and talk to them.
She turns to Vukradin perhaps you with your silver tongue can can help this, but, but we are, this, it's imperative.
I worry that if what's her name?
The intervention or the naturalists are able to convince the druids, the local druids, that whatever evil forces have produced, these incursions will now lose a powerful ally for us to defend the communities.
Yeah, we need all the allies we can get.
All right, so we'll start with that next week.
All right, yep.
Sounds good.
All right.
So, yes.
Sorry, I should have added one more thing.
He goes, I've heard rumors that some, then he goes, The only caution I give you, Soma, is that there are some there who have suggested that they should even evaluate whether you should retain the staff.
They're not taking it from me.
This has at least sentimental value.
He goes, I did not want to.
I agree with you.
A staff that no order can take my sword.
He pats his sword, you know.
A little barbarous, but yeah, I get you.
He pats the sword.
A man's sword, a man's sword.
I don't know what I have been told that staffs with druids are like a spider's sword or a barbarian's.
Is that a halberd?
Big stabby pokey thing.
Because that is a very fine halberd, Brewbarry.
Yes, it is.
We should parry.
You don't want to have a conversation with it, trust me.
I don't.
I can see why not.
All right.
Okay.
So yes, there is that also subtext.
All right, guys.
All right.
See you guys next week.
See you next week.
Yep.
Thanks.